Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services, I have been working in the corporate sector for 13 years and have an MBA in finance
and today I am presenting to you the Century
Plan of PNB Mat Life Insurance. This is an excellent product launched by the company, where you
get income from the first month till 100 years. This is a non-linked plan, a participating
plan, where you also get the benefits of bonus and maturity also comes, plus
the company has given an excellent option of family care, suppose you take that option
and the proposer dies, then the death benefit will be immediately given to the family,
the premium payment will be waived, the income you were getting will continue for 100 years,
maturity will also come, so I am giving you information in full details of this plan,
watch this video and if you like the video, then definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS,
thank you, now let's understand all the benefits and features of this plan. The name of the plan
is Century Plan, where you Income is received for up to 100 years and tax benefits are also available
and if you need, you can amortize your benefits according to your benefit and you
can also withdraw them when needed. First of all, here
you will get insurance cover for whole life, it is a legacy for the family because
you get a very large amount on maturity, you will get cash bonuses which
will be 10 percent of your annual premium if you select the option of super income and
if you select the option of future income, you will get it on 30 percent, there are three options in this,
I will explain all three to you in detail, apart from this,
there is an option of family care, which I will explain to you in detail that if you
take that option, then if the proposer dies, in that case all
the premiums will be waived, the family
will immediately get the insurance and the income that was to come will continue and maturity will also come and
apart from this, you can also utilize it as retirement
and if you You can also accumulatively calculate the income that is coming,
so these are the main points of this plan. Now in this plan, three
options have been given to you for income, one is the super income option,
the second option is called smart income option and the third is future income
option, all three are the same. Let us understand all these three options before this, let us
see the eligibility criteria as to who can take this policy,
what is the premium payment term etc. I will tell you a little about it, so here let us see
the policy term, all premium payments are available, family care option which
I have told you, what does it mean, with family care option, without family care option,
if you take option one, the option of super income, then you
will get maturity till 80 years, you can take the policy till the maximum age of 80 and if you take without family care, then
you can take this policy till 100 years, the same will remain in smart income option and future income
option, in this way, if we talk about premium payment term,
in without family care option you will get maturity of 5 years, 6 years, 7 years The premium payment terms are for 8 years, 9 years and 10 years.
Apart from this, you can also make premium payment for 12 and 15 years.
In With Family Care as well, you are given premium payment options in the same manner. Talking about
the entry age, a person from 30 days old to 65 years old
can purchase this policy. Talking about the minimum insurance cover, it is ₹ lakh and without it,
you will get 240000.
So now let's look at these three options. Let's look at the first
option, the Super Income option. What will you get in the Super Income option? Firstly,
you will get guaranteed cash bonus in survival benefit
and one cash bonus. What about guaranteed cash bonus?
The rules will be that if you have taken Without Family Care Benefit and
your premium payment term is 10 years or more, then you will get 10% of the premium, otherwise you
will get 5%. In With Family Care Benefit, if you are paying premium for more than 10 years, then you will get 5%
off annual premium. Otherwise, you will get % off annual premium. Apart from this, you will get cash
bonus which the company declares every year. So, I will explain this now.
As an example, let's assume there is a person named
Anil Rajpat who is 35 years old and he is purchasing the policy of PNB MetLife
Century Plan in which he will pay premium for 12 years, ₹1 lakh annual
premium. So, now here we see the option selected
is Super Income Option, which I am explaining to you. He
has taken Super Income Option which will run for 100 years and here he has selected Family Care Benefit
If you have not taken it, what will happen in that case and the bonus type is cash bonus
and here the annual premium is ₹ 1 lakh, the basic sum is ₹ 1 lakh
from day one and the death benefit is ₹ 1 lakh from day one with GST, your premium
will be ₹ 4500 in the first year and from the second year it will keep increasing by ₹ 2250
for the remaining 11 years, now let's see how it will be, first you are paying ₹ 1 lakh premium, so
here the guaranteed benefit is written, minimum guaranteed cash bonus, this is written guaranteed,
so it is written on 10, as I told you in the example, if the premium payment
is for more than 10 years, then you will get it on 10, so here you got 10 p00 of b plus you
will get cash bonus, for cash bonus you can see the column at 4 and the column at 8,
so if I tell you from the column at 8, then you will get a cash bonus of ₹ 1,600, column number 11 If
you look at column number 15, 1 +
11 + 12, so 1 + 11 plus 12, after adding these three, your income will be
26400. You will start getting income annually from the first year itself.
After the premium payment term, your income will increase here, like it is becoming 5300 here because the cash bonus
is increasing and the guaranteed 10000 that was coming here will stop and
you will keep getting this income. You will get income for life time
and on maturity, you will see that you get a maturity of one crore rupees which
you can use as a legacy in the family. If the company gives a bonus of 4%, then
you will get a maturity of 500 rupees, but if it is declared at 8%, then you will get 76 lakh rupees.
Insurance cover will also be yours from day one. Death benefit and this death benefit will be there. Let me tell you in the benefit
column,
you can see column number 19, here your insurance cover is 1176 400 and it
will keep increasing after some time, you can see it keeps increasing, it
goes up to 17 lakh 30 lakh 32 lakh and above one crore, apart from this, the option of surrender benefit is also given, you
can also see the column of surrender benefit that if you go to surrender,
what amount will you get at that time, so this is the first option where they
did not select the family care option, if they select it, suppose here I
will also tell you that they have selected the family care benefit option, yes, in that
case what difference will come, same you see here, come down, the income which
was going to come at 10, it will come at 5, like here I told you that you will get income at 5, if
you have selected the family care option, then you will get this income at 5
and you will also get cash bonus, so you will see the cash bonus here,
000 instead of 16000 If these are received, then in total you were getting 26000, here
you will get 9721, here you were getting 52000, here you will get 39000, if you
select this option and on maturity also 1 crore 77 something was going to be given or
you will get 1.66 crore, so this but what will be the benefit of taking this option that
for
example a customer paid three premiums, unfortunately he died,
in that case the family will get 1 lakh rupees immediately, the rest of the premiums will be waived,
the company will pay, PNB will pay the amount, the income that you are getting of 19721,
after that 3968, this will continue and on maturity you
will also get 1 crore 67 lakh, so now you have to select whether you want this income of 39000 or
52000, but if there is death, then which option will be better for you,
you can decide this on your own. You can select as per your need. Now let's talk about option number two,
smart income option. In this, there is no guaranteed income. You only
get bonuses in this. So let's understand this as well. The customer is 35 years old and he is
selecting the option for smart income this time. He is not taking the family care benefit here.
He is selecting cash bonus. He is paying a premium of Rs. 1 lakh only. So what
difference will it make? See, you don't see anything in guaranteed benefit here.
But if you look at the bonus here, you will
start getting a bonus of Rs. 33750 from the first year itself. After the premium payment term, your income will keep increasing
and on maturity you will get bonuses. So, your income
will also keep increasing from time to time. If you take the family care benefit option here, yes,
then how much income would you get? 1000, then it would increase to 10000, then it would increase to 35000
and maximum 42000. On maturity, you get ₹ 56 lakhs
but in case of death, the premium payment will be waived. 115 lakhs
will be received immediately. Income of Rs. 25, 300 will keep coming continuously. All these options will be available here as well.
Let's talk about option number three, future income option, future income option
In this you will get two more things, one guaranteed benefit, that too you
will get cash bonus and also you will get a fixed income option. If we talk about
how much guaranteed you will get, then you will get it on 30% of annual premium and with family care you
will get it on 10% and the definition of fixed income is all your
accumulated acute simple bonuses divided by fixed income period, the fixed income period will be 100
years if your policy term is then you will have fixed income for 30 years and if
the policy term is 80 years in that case you will have fixed income for 20 years, so I
will also explain to you how it works, let's see the third option, in the third option future
income option is taken, the policy will run till 100 years, the family care option
is not selected, so now look here, firstly
you have started getting
income of one lakh on 30%, secondly you have cash bonus, the cash bonus of
76600 will be visible here in column number 11
and The third is fixed income. Who gets fixed income? Fixed income is available.
It is a revisionary bonus. The total amount declared till that time, divided by
fixed income, say Rs 10, Rs 28,400, you had accumulated.
If you divide it by 30 years, you will get 9613. So in this way, you
will get 9613 + 76600 plus 30,000. By adding these three,
you will get future income. By adding these three, you
get 11213. Here, you can also see in the column where it came from.
If you do 1 + 11 + 12, you will get this income.
11213. This income will start coming to you, but this income will start after 15 years. It
is not starting from the first year. And on maturity, you will get Rs 5 lakh.
Now, in this policy also, in this option, if you add the family benefit care option.
If you say yes to this option, then what? There will be benefits
. Here, instead of the income of 1000 that you were supposed to get,
you will get an income of 10000 and on maturity, you will get 1 crore 18 lakhs instead of 75 lakhs. In the earlier plan,
you were getting 75 lakhs for merit but here you are getting 1 crore 18 72000
but in 4%, there is only 92000. So, in this way, which
option do you want to select according to your need? You can select that option whether you
want immediate income or income in future, you want income from the first month or after 15 years.
If you want to accumulate this income and deposit it, you
can deposit it as well. If you want to withdraw it, you can withdraw it as well.
You
will get that benefit as per the reverse repo rate. And if there is any benefit in this policy, I will explain it a little bit.
I have already explained this benefit to you. I
have already told you the maturity benefit. Meaning of family care benefit I have already told you that
you will get the column of benefits, you can see it from there
and I have also told you about the bonus that the company declares every year. Loan is also available.
In this policy, you will get loan up to 80% of the surrender value. There are also riders in it. There
is accidental death benefit rider. The company has
provided you a rider of 10 critical incidents in this policy. Apart from this, there is flexible premium payment term.
The free look period will also be of 15 days. You will also
get a grace period of 30 days. You can see the surrender benefit. You will get revival time of 5 years.
If you are unable to pay the policy on time due to any reason, then you
can continue the policy by taking all the money together anytime in 5 years. There is a free look period of 15 days.
You will get income tax benefit in this policy. So if you like the video, then
more than 3 videos of life insurance, health insurance, motor
insurance are already available on YouTube. You can also go there and buy similar
products of other companies. You can also compare the videos that have been made to decide
which one is better for you. Thank you so much, Jai
Hind.